I'm going to try doing something that
I'm warned doesn't work on YouTube I'm
going to answer the question posed in
the title right away if you're not
Japanese and want to visit our come Liv
in kofu toori you are as far as I can
tell quite welcome hello world welcome
to kofu if you didn't catch it I made a
video about this small Japanese town and
there were a lot of commenters either
saying that they had interest in
visiting or that foreigners shouldn't go
there and ruin the town well a month
after the video's released I visited the
town again and this is what they wanted
to show me
[Music]
I don't know how long this video will be
but I'm guessing it'll be at least half
an hour by the time we're done exploring
the question of foreigners in this rural
Japanese Town there's a lot of ground to
cover as such I went to kofu with my
part-time producer and full-time
sister-in-law AKO for 5 days which was
not enough but it's what we could do
while in kofu we tried as best as
possible to see if a the town actually
wants an increase in foreign residents
or visitors and B how this could all
work out both for the town and the
potential newcomers we try to answer
questions like where would you stay how
would you get around how would you
access essential services and how would
you fit into the community is it really
possible or advisable for non-japanese
to live here so we looked at different
accommodations both for short and
long-term stay we investigated getting
around by train bus bike and car we went
to the clinic we once again talked with
the mayor we looked at volunteer
opportunities we saw how different town
programs worked and we heard the stories
of more members of the community overall
we tried to find out as much as we could
about the town however I know I won't be
able to answer all your questions
that'll get some things wrong and
information will change so I did
something I've never done before which
is to set up a Discord server apparently
I'm doing lots of new things for those
of you who don't know what Discord is
it's basically an online chat group like
Facebook groups my patreon supporters
helped me to set it up so thank you all
for that I've posted an unofficial guide
to kofu there and I hope it can be a
place for those interested in kofu to
ask questions connect and get help even
though my previous video received over
2.4 million views in 3 months who knows
how many people are actually serious
about visiting our living in kofu so to
help the town judge interest and see
who's interested I made a up a short
questionnaire links to the Discord and
questionnaire in the description and one
last thing before we get into the video
let me just address the word Foreigner
that I'll use throughout it in Japanese
when talking about someone who's not
from Japan gu kokuin is often used
Google Translates it as Foreigner when
we were talking with the mayor we often
used the word Kay nohito which literally
means people from overseas among
foreigners the word gin is often used
which can be considered rude if a person
were to address a foreigner in this way
the word Foreigner can have a lot of
negative connotations especially in 2025
so when you see it in the subtitles or
hear me saying it it's simply meant in a
neutral way to talk about a person who's
not Japanese and I know I know who's
considered to be Japanese I made a whole
documentary about that so you can watch
that if you really want to explore that
topic now perhaps you've already seen my
previous video but even if you have
maybe you forgot something things so
here's a quick overview of kofu hello
world we're back in kofo the least
populated town in toori which is the
prefecture with the least population in
all of Japan kofu population is
currently 2 and a half thousand and it's
been on the decline ever since the 1950s
when their population was three times as
large it's located on the back side of
the Majestic Mount Dyson and its main
claim to fame is the quality of their
water
oh which is why santor has one of their
bottling factories located in town its
other Big Money Maker is its
hydroelectric Dam it's about a 30 minute
or so commute to Yono city which has a
population of
145,000 since there's no High School in
town this is where high schoolers get
their learning on and many of their
parents do their daily work grind kofu
is an absolutely beautiful town where
half its residents are over the age of
65 it also has a lot of abandoned homes
which is probably why many viewers were
asking if they would be able to live
there so we sat down with the mayor in
the city's trial home and asked
[Music]
hi I'd like to book a hotel room for the
night do you have anything available
yes we can provide Japanese and Western
rooms okay what's the cost for
them okay so if you know Japanese and
English the translation isn't perfect
but it can get the job done
so
for for
IND
[Music]
so AKO was consistently pressing the
mayor trying to find the GOA that moment
where they say well actually it'd be
better if foreigners didn't come
because so and so but that never
happened and then just reviewing all
this footage reviewing our time there it
seemed obvious that of course foreigners
could go and live in kofu many have in
the past and many are doing so today and
the way I came up with to explain it in
increasing complexity how a foreigner
might live in Japan is to break get down
into the lengths of stay and the
difficulty involved first there is easy
mode where you're only visiting for a
number of days second there's medium
mode where you're visiting for a few
weeks or months and lastly there's hard
mode where you're staying for a year or
more so in this first part of the video
I'll address how one would visit a town
like kofu for a few days easy mode so
you're in Japan on a visitor visa and
wanted to drop by kofu and get a taste
of rural Japan how do you even get here
you have Planes Trains and Automobiles
one might think that plane would be the
easiest but if you're flying from within
Japan there's only one option the ANA
flight from haneda airport in Tokyo to
Yono airport in toori there are six
daily flights which is convenient enough
but this would assume that you're
starting close enough to Han airport for
this option to make sense but let's say
you do take that then you'd end up at
Yono airport if you're going to train it
in to EBY state station in kofu then
you're in luck because the airport has A
train station a few hundred meters walk
from the airport from there you would
transfer once at Yogo station before
arriving in kofu and the whole trip only
takes an hour if you happen to board at
the perfect time chances are your timing
won't work out so well or that it'll
make more sense to use a bus for part of
the trip so it's more likely to take an
hour and a half or 2 hours but it's
easily doable of course you could get a
rental car from the airport which would
logistically make not only easier to get
to kofu but get around it once you've
arrived and if you're only going to kofu
for a few days this will financially not
be too expensive as you can easily get
rental cars for under 10,000 Yen a day
all you need is a proper IDP
international driver's permit and now
that you know that rental cars are
doable you can take that travel method
and figure out that you could easily
drive in from okama airport our station
in 1 and 1/2 to 2 hours okama airport
has way more flights available and
oklahama station is serviced by the
Shonen the bullet train which has an
incredible frequency of trains that
don't require you to book far in advance
depending on the time you're traveling
you might want to book in advance but
the majority of the time it's not
necessary so you could take a rental car
from oklahama airport or oklahama
station but you could also take the
yakumo limited Express train if I didn't
want to or wasn't able to hire a rental
car this is what I would do if you're
used to the Comfort level and service of
a shin conen train then you'll know what
to expect it'll be a nice train ride the
train will take you to na station from
which point you can hop onto a local
train for an 8-minute ride to EBY
station or if the connection timing
doesn't work out because local trains
only run every couple hours sometimes
then you can take a taxi to the station
it's only a 10-minute car ride and
lastly you could take the bus in from
Osaka or coob if you're lucky you can
get to kofu in 3 and 1/2 hours but most
likely will take you 5 and 1/2 hours as
you'll need to transfer and take a train
in from
Yono once you're in town where do you
sleep this is actually difficult to
answer currently there's only one active
in that's close to the station if you
look at it in Google Maps it would
repair you can only book it by phone but
if you search around you'll see that
they do allow booking via Airbnb so that
would be the obvious choice if you want
to stay in the Town Center there were
two other ends that were operating only
a few years ago but then Co hit and the
ins decided to close down the operators
of both inss now only sell food there
weren't enough guests to make business
worthwhile The Operators are also past
retirement age so I don't think there
are any plans to reopen I could be wrong
but my feeling is that most outof Town
visitors come to kofu for the nature so
they wouldn't want to stay next to the
station anyways they'd much prefer the
only other lodging that's open in the
town of kofu which is camura Oken
they're located way up in the mountains
a 25-minute drive from May station they
have a public bath and provide breakfast
and dinner so it's what a lot of
Japanese visitors look for and is thus
the recommended spot to stay at if you
have a rental car this is an easy
recommendation if you don't then you
could get there on the free shuttle bus
or take a taxi if you're a resident of
kofu with no ability to drive the taxi
has special rates to get you around but
you're not that so you'd pay the regular
rate which I'm told is about 2,000 Yen
for the oneway trip now the distance is
only 17 kilometers so theoretically you
could ride a bike there and the city's
Visitor Center does offer electric bike
rentals however I'm assuming most
visitors wouldn't want to do this and if
you do you have to book The Bike 2 days
in advance this lack of accommodations
is why a lot of visitors will either
stay in Yono a 30-minute drive or Huen a
20-minute drive and it's also why so
many people would say having an
automobile is a must once you have your
transportation and accommodation squared
away what do you actually do where do
you eat a reason camura is a recommended
choice is because they not only have
food but they have nature walks and
nighttime stargazing if you're into
nature then there are so many beautiful
spots to hit up which you can easily do
by a car and if you're into the active
lifestyle you could use that electric
bike rental to cycle all around you can
rent one for 500 yen an hour between
9:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. they currently
don't have any longer rental plans but
if you ask them they might be able to
accommodate you and if you're really
active you can book a session at the big
mountain rooms BMX Center as a note
you'll have to book this in advance I
personally love Dairy so I visited Dyson
makiba milk Village that's not
technically in kofu but about a
20-minute drive from it I also love Hot
Springs so I went to the Oceanside K
onen resort area in Yono which is
roughly a 30-minute drive from the of
kofu both the milk Village and hot
springs have standard operating hours so
you should have no problem visiting but
a place you'll need to book way in
advance is beastro noou it's a husband
and wife team that operates this the
wife having grown up in kofu they used
to run the business in Tokyo where they
had a bib gourmont Michelin designation
for places with no appointments
necessary the go-to recommendation seems
to be the okua and roadside station they
have regular predictable hours for your
lunch meal but unfortunately no
breakfast or dinner although technically
from 9:30 a.m. you can have a coffee or
ice cream there and even buy some food
from the attached gift shop and eat it
there but if you're looking online you'd
probably never know this on Google Maps
it says the restaurant opens up only
from 11 a.m. to 2: p.m. while the
farmers market side is open from 9:00
a.m. to 3:00 p.m. but if you look at
their website you'll see that the gift
shop is open from 8:30 a.m. to 5:30 p.m.
and the vending machines and bathrooms
are open 24/7 however it's only going
there and asking about getting a coffee
that they told us we can sit down and
eat food bought at the gift shop in
their seating area and this all brings
me to a point that I think is very
important to know Finding reliable
accurate up-to-date information about
places you want to visit in rural Japan
is not possible to do completely online
even if you think a place is closed or a
place is open I found the only real way
to know is to give them a phone call and
see which will almost always require you
to know how to speak basic Japanese
there are times when you can text email
or message to find out the information
but whether or not you get a timely
response depends on who's on the other
side the reason I like phone calls is
because I'm old well maybe but for me
it's because with a phone call you can
instantly get an answer and ask
follow-up questions whereas with text
you don't know when you'll get an answer
if ever in rule Japan there are so many
instances where the information posted
online is out of date or an owner
decides to on a whim to take the day off
or close early but if you can get the
correct information you can enjoy some
nice Little Gems like this Cafe that was
closed the first time we tried to visit
but was open for lunch on the last day
we were in town and haha checking them
on Google Maps it's currently listed as
open only on Thursdays and Fridays
between 11:00 a.m. and 2: p.m. there's
no link to their website but when I
searched their name I found they had a
website and they're listed as open
Monday through Friday but closed on
weekends and holidays what's the
accurate schedule unless you call I
don't think you'd really know in this
case they have an Instagram that they
post their schedule to on a timely
enough basis that I believe you can
trust it all this uncertainty is why we
often ate at Lawson which is open 24/7
365 and has a big selection of ready to
eat meals and I think that covers all
the major points about visiting kofu as
a tourist for a few days with a car and
translation app you should have no
problem getting by unfortunately you
can't trust online information about
whether accommodations activities or
food is available as posted the best way
to do it is by phone but this gets very
tough if you're not in the country and
don't speak Japanese there is a
sightseeing information center that has
open 7 days a week between 9:00 a.m. and
5:00 p.m. but they don't speak English
however we did talk with them and
they're completely comfortable using
translation apps and they also welcome
questions via email and they even said
you can use them as a kind of hotel
conare service so they can book
activities for you or call restaurants
to make reservations I think this could
be very handy by the way if you visit
kofu you might come across eicha the
town's tourism Ambassador she's on
posters and cutouts all over the place
she even has her own Twitter and
Instagram account and as I found out
when I visited vised the town's Visitor
Center her own merch medium mode easy
mode for staying in kofu for a few days
is like hard mode for those that have
experienced a tourist friendly City like
Tokyo kto or Osaka so what's medium mode
and kofu like this is for people who
want to stay a week or two or even a
month or two I'm assuming you won't want
to stay in a hotel room that has no
kitchen facilities you're probably
looking for an Airbnb kind of
accommodation of which there are none a
in in the previous video we visited a
trial home run by the nonprofit
relocation Association kofu noote and
this time around we even got to stay in
it for a few
days technically anyone can register for
this place so this is theoretically an
option but there's only this single
place and it's meant for people who are
thinking about moving to kofu so I don't
know if it's a realistic one so we
talked with the mayor about what kind of
options have for short-term visitors and
there were basically none that's right
none you might have also seen that home
from the previous video that you can
rent but rents for those kinds of homes
aren't for people visiting for a short
term it's for those that are staying in
kofu for a year or longer so you might
be out of luck if you want a short-term
stay in a weekly or monthly rental type
of accommodation however the mayor
thinks that a new law might change
things up for for the
better for
so
I'm sure you're curious as to what some
of these potential short-term stay
accommodations might be I was so I set
out to see a couple of them the first
being a former ski
resort it's now partially used as a
nature school one of seven across the
country it's run by the town and the
mayor is the
principal when I had initially heard
about everland it seemed like the
perfect place to potentially house a lot
of visitors as I had thought it was a
ski resort that had been closed down
however I didn't realize that while that
was true the facility that was built was
a chalet and not a lodging facility so
while it can host a hundred or probably
more people for meals it wasn't designed
to house any people overnight we found
that they have a collection of rooms
such as this little meeting room or this
nurse's office where you can
theoretically place people also the side
room which is being used as a temporary
office and then there's this huge room
that's outfitted with tatami mats in
order to accommodate student groups that
visit futons will be placed on them and
then large groups of students can sleep
there overnight but the only shower
facilities in the place are attached to
the office where the Rangers are located
and there are only two shower booths
with one attached to the male locker
room and the other attached to the
female one so I would say the structure
is in very good condition since it was
built in 1999 it's up to the latest
earthquake codes
however its current design is not meant
for individual lodging and would require
some extensive renovations to get the
Proper bathing facilities and private
sleeping areas needed to house groups of
people for anything more than a couple
of days but if the place were converted
it really is in a beautiful area that I
feel would be very attractive for those
looking to get away from it all one
downside to the location is that it's up
in the mountains so without a car you'd
really be stuck up there it's 12 km from
the town C Center so you could manage
commuting with an electric bike but it'
be really tough come winter
[Music]
so everland looks like it has good
potential in a few years but that won't
help anyone out right now a different
place that I did look at seems like it
has a lot more potential it's a former
elementary school that's been partly
converted into a twice a week Medical
Clinic it's designed to service the
locals in this part of town sometimes
students from toor University will come
here to do field work as well
unlike the everland ski resort this has
two different shower rooms with both the
male and female side having two showers
each there are several classroom size
sleeping rooms and they already have all
the sleeping and cooking equipment
necessary to house a decently sized
group of people all the rooms are set up
with air cone units and heaters the
whole place is recently renovated so
it's in very good condition and would be
an excellent place to temporarily house
groups of people for events like a
festival this place is also used as a
community center and I heard they have
singing and dancing events the thing is
though this place isn't run by the town
so whether this could be a possible
place to house short stay visitors is
uncertain we also saw that once a week
on Thursdays they' run a lunch program
for local residents in the surrounding
[Music]
area for
but let's see you figure out where to
stay how do you get around we visited a
couple car rental agencies in Yono City
and both of them quoted a price of
around 150,000 Yen per month to rent a
car they don't have monthly rental rates
we then searched online and were able to
find some places that would rent you a
car for under 100,000 Yen which is a lot
more reasonable if you're thinking you
could purchase our Lisa car you need to
have a resident card to do so which you
won't obtain on a short-term stay Visa
that tourists would get theoretically
you could purchase a bike and if you
live close enough to EBY station you
could get most places you'd want to in
under 15 minutes for example the
roadside station with the farmers market
is right next to the Lawson and the
small Supermarket while your variety
would be limited you could easily pick
up enough to survive this is only a 2 km
bike ride which we did just to be sure
and if you rod in the opposite direction
towards M station that's where you'll
find nanao salon which is their free- to
use co-working space many of you asked
about the speed of the internet here's
the
answer I'll talk more about the salon
and how it works as well as Internet
speeds but I want to Circle back to the
bike situation The Visitors Center bike
rentals won't be a good option for
anything more than a day or two but as
far as I can tell unlike an automobile
you can purchase a bike without a
resident card there's actually a bike
shop right next to Ebby station where
you could do this for cycling around
kofu even though there are no dedicated
bike paths that I'm aware of the fastest
roads are only 50 km or 31 mph there's
very little traffic on the mountain
roads so I think most regular cyclists
would feel safe enough the road with the
most traffic would be route to 181 that
passes by the roadside station and the
two train stations technically you would
need to ride on the road but you're
allowed to go on the sidewalk if you
deem the road dangerous or if you're a
child senior or disabled in practice
provided you're not speeding around on
the sidewalk and you're given priority
to the rare pedestrian you might
encounter it'll probably be okay to
cycle on the sidewalk on this stretch of
this road this is one of those things
that I debate about publishing online
because I honestly feel it's much safer
for cyclists and car drivers on a road
like this if a casual cyclist were to
ride on the sidewalk here like AO is
doing are in a section like this where
there's very little shoulder to ride on
but for a portion of road like this
where the traffic is slower I think it's
perfectly safe alongside the road like
I'm doing here in any case I think you
could get away with using an electric
bike and commuting within the town if
you wanted
to I had initially thought you'd have a
really tough time without a car but I'm
starting to rethink this in the winter
is really where I think you'd have the
toughest time but I'm trying to get out
there in the winter so I'll try it out
and report back if I
can all right so back to the co-working
[Music]
space our in English rainbow Salon it's
free to use as long as you sign up I'd
say the internet speed is fairly decent
from a video Creator's perspective I
could always get more speed but for I'm
assuming the vast majority of people 100
megabits per second is more than enough
at this speed you can transfer 10 gbt of
data in 13 minutes so if you want to get
some work done you're always free to
drop by between 9:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m.
Monday to Friday if you want to use it
at night or on weekends you can call
their number and that can be arranged if
you want to reserve the entire place you
can book times anywhere between between
9:00 a.m. and 10: p.m. a useful thing is
that they have a full kitchen complete
with IH stove water boiler fridge and
microwave by the time we wanted to eat
lunch the restaurants in town were
already closed as it was 2 p.m. so we
picked up some cup noodles to eat oh and
for the washroom they have barrier-free
facilities there are a couple
semi-private booths an area for young
kids some Booth seating and then some
regular seating I've seen pictures of
the space in different configurations so
I imagine it's okay to temporarily
rearrange things to suit your needs I
think the only thing to be aware of is
that since it's a coold workking space
you should keep down your volume if
there are other people around but what
about the speed of internet outside of
the cafe if you're in an area that can
get a fiber connection like this which
I'm told is all over town you can get
similar speeds if you only have your
cell phone the data speeds will really
depend on your proximity to the cell
towers for example a in the mountains
the cell phone signal would occasionally
drop but then get strong in certain
areas like up at the former ski
resort unfortunately in the tri home
right by EBY station it was set up with
Wi-Fi that was using cell phone data so
the speeds were limited and there were
data caps I found that my smartphone
with dok service got faster and more
reliable bandwidth so I switched to that
when I wanted video calls that were fast
fter than 10 frames per minute I know
something that viewers wanted to know
was how the medical services were I was
expecting to see a tiny clinic but when
I was able to step into the reception
area it was quite bigger and seemingly
well equipped than what I thought it
would be this city run Clinic has
limited operating hours from Monday to
Friday between 9:00 a.m. and 12:00 p.m.
and are also open on some Saturdays by
appointment during the afternoons the
doctors will do house calls the doctors
are on a rotating schedule and don't
necessarily live in kofu but rather
commute in even if you don't have
insurance you can still pay cash and
visit with a doctor if paying cash
sounds scary I wouldn't fret since the
firsttime visit fee is 3,000 yen for
anything big like surgeries the Hino
hospital is only a 10-minute drive away
if for some reason you needed even more
Specialized Care there's the toor
University Hospital located in Yono
which is a half-hour driveway
some viewers were wondering if they
could do volunteer work around town so
we asked the mayor if they had any
systems in place to accommodate
them
for
[Music]
for for
and the following day we went to the
silver jinai Center but before we pop
the question about foreign volunteers we
asked them to Simply explain what they
[Music]
do
for for
[Music]
hi for
and then we ask the big question if
there are foreigners that want to
volunteer could they use their help
and this is a situation where physically
being somewhere you're researching is
great we quickly hopped in the car and
drove the 25 minutes to camura okua to
see if we could catch the silver team in
action
for
[Music]
spe
for
[Applause]
speee for
[Music]
m
okay so let's level up and get to living
in kofu on hard mode now I know the
mayor said that you can use a
translation app or that you could phone
a friend you can but I think it' get
tricky on both sides and a bit
frustrating too however I found out that
there's the totor prefectural
International Exchange Foundation which
has volunteer community interpreters to
help when visiting medical or government
facilities think visiting a doctor
registering for a high school getting a
driver's license or registering your
address with the city but the closest
office is in Yono about a half hour away
so we wanted to know if there was
someone among all the viewers who was
bilingual and could help out with these
kinds of things would they be interested
in such a person
now there's a difference between talking
about possibilities and actually
following through I've been told that
the town will be posting a regional
revitalization position on their website
the start date April
2025 the requirements are are specific
in that you need to be located in a
major Japanese City and be willing to
relocate to kofu for a 3-year contract
so you couldn't be moving in from a
small Japanese Town nor from anywhere
else in the world but if this is you or
someone you know they'll have the job
posted on the town's website a seemingly
big appeal of the inaka the countryside
of Japan is cheap land and housing I had
read that the town rents out housing so
I of course wanted to
investigate for
[Music]
I don't know why this didn't click in
right away but what I was looking at was
public housing and the units I saw the
exterior of seem to be in very good
shape so it's no wonder that there are
no vacancies
so as we found out there's simply not
enough affordable housing rentals
there's only 30 for a town of 2 half
thousand now now there is a big stock of
abandoned properties and land but as we
also found out it's not easy or quick or
cheap to renovate or build new so for a
newcomer who wants to come and just
simply have a nice place to live it's
not so easy and another note that I got
from the town was that while there are
many vacant Lots there are many that are
not zoned for building residential units
on them some have Farmland attached
where you would need to go through the
agricultural committee to purchase it
some don't have the inheritance
registration completed so they cannot be
purchased immediately there are also red
zones which are special Landslide prone
areas where you need permission from the
prefecture to build new I didn't get a
picture of this but while driving into
the town I noticed that part of a hill
had washed away what I did get video of
is some concrete reinforcement work that
has been done to protect an area from
landslides but let's say you don't mind
a fixer upper and all the work that may
be associated with it that's where kofu
noori comes in handy they're a nonprofit
that helps people relocate to kofu by
both helping them find housing and
integrate but also to get businesses set
up in the last video we saw a house that
was in very good condition what you
would call moving ready they had lights
Heron appliances and it looked like
everything Beyond beding most places in
Japan will require you to buy and
install all those things so this time we
asked to see one of the worst examples
they have of a house that isn't moving
ready
at first I thought an animal had gotten
in and defecated all over the
place but we quickly realized it was
soba or in other words buck weat that
was spilling out from a pillow or
something while the place was most
certainly not moving ready I was
expecting worse like water leaks mold
and rotting floors instead what I found
was a place where all the belongings
were left in place and it was a lot of
stuff but otherwise it didn't seem to be
in especially bad shape it feels like
the place got ransacked but without the
physical damage
[Music]
now everyone knows that nothing is
exactly free so if you took it over
you'd be responsible for transfer taxes
property taxes and a host of other
expenses that could run you 500,000 to 1
million yen and then you need to clear
the place out and make sure the water
electricity hot water and heating are
all working or fixed up which could be
who knows how much and then you'd most
likely want to fix up or replace
cosmetic things things whether it's the
tatami mats or wallpaper there's also a
backyard which is absolutely overgrown
and has a ton of crap piled up but if
you cleared it all out you'd actually
have a decent amount of space or at
least by Tokyo standards the only thing
missing is a parking space but I'm
confident that'd be easily solvable by
renting out one of the many vacant Lots
around the area and I wrote this out
before taking another look at the
property because it does look like you
could park a small car in the front on a
different day we were taken to the area
where there were a couple abandoned
homes for purchase or rent the first
house was in what I consider very good
shape provided the utilities have no
issues I think you could start moving in
your stuff and live here in short order
and if you wanted to rent or buy the
place
the second house was not in as great a
condition as the first and came with no
parking our yard to rent it would be
cheaper but for purchase the price or
option to do so was undecided the big
thing to know is that even if the
purchase or rental price isn't expensive
it's all the other cost that you need to
consider utilities on an older place are
going to be much more expensive as there
can be virtually no insulation and
everything is not as efficient so that's
why you might get confused at the
estimated cost of housing depending on
who you talk to nakaa said that if you
get a property you can spend 10 million
or 20 million yen to renovate it I can
easily see that happening especially if
you want to upgrade everything to modern
day standards but I can also see that if
you were able to do some of the work
yourself and your selective what you
upgrade you could get away with
Renovations that cost half of those
amounts all right let's say you did it
you found a house you want to live in
that house will be located in one of
kof's many many communities do you know
its specific rules will you become an
accepted
member for
so this
[Music]
m for
yeah
[Music]
e
for for
[Music]
yeah so this this is one of those things
that I found so fascinating in my mind a
small town was a single entity so I
never considered that you may fit into
one part of it but not the other however
I've recently been visiting a lot of
small towns and now I understand better
that you can't generalized and whether
you'll be a good match for the place may
just depend on your immediate neighbors
I'm sure you could say this about big
cities like Tokyo but I feel like over
there you're less reliant on your
neighbors so you don't need your
relationships to be as strong out in the
rural areas up in the mountains when
your power goes out or you get stuck in
the snow your neighbors may be the only
people that'll be able to help you out
this whole fitting into the community
thing is part of why the relocation no
exists as they can set you up in a trial
home to get used to the town and then
help you tour different neighborhoods to
see if you'll be a good match for the
community now all of this fitting into
to the community talk may not even be
relevant to a lot of you viewers as you
may not have the citizenship residency
or VISA to live in Japan long term visas
are such a big and complicated topic too
much for the scope of this video so what
I will say is that anything we're
talking about we're assuming you have
the proper visa to stay as a visitor or
resident and are following the rules of
what the Visa allows you to do I'm
assuming the Visa that most visitors
could get is the 90-day short-term stay
one which Japan issues to citizens of
many many countries there is a new
digital know at Visa that allows you to
do remote work from Japan for a maximum
of 6 months in a year if you make above
10 million yen at your job then this
could be a good solution for you
generally speaking all the other visas
require you to be a student to have a
Japanese employer that's sponsoring you
or for you to have some family
connection to Japan like a spouse there
is a business investor visa you could
get if you have a bit of money so if you
want to start something up maybe that's
a possibility I'll leave a link to a
subred where they talk in detail about
Visa requirements I'd recommend talking
to an immigration lawyer if you're
looking for something Beyond a visitor
visa and hey if there's enough interest
perhaps I'll do an interview with One in
the
[Music]
future for
I did ask the town what benefit they
would expect to get from digital Nomads
and they responded that there wasn't a
direct Financial benefit as the digital
Nomad would pay taxes to their home
country but the mayor thought it would
make the town more lively and perhaps it
could provide some good International
exchange opportunities so he's very much
welcoming them this ties in with what
you should really expect if you want to
come live in kofu now I don't remember
who exactly said this but the idea is
that if you're coming to kofu expecting
to find paid work there is no paid work
sorry however if you want to come in and
volunteer if you want to bring your own
work by starting a business or being a
digital Nomad or if you want to come as
a tourist then please come you're more
than welcome
the more time we spent in kofu the more
we met people that relocated from other
areas last time we did a little
interview with endoa who I called Mr
Coffee when we popped by again he was
doing
[Music]
great this time we talked with um who
moved to kofu from
Tokyo
for for
[Laughter]
another interesting migrant was Tomy
nagasa who operates the BMX facility run
out of an aband in school the last time
we went to visit there was no one there
this time Tomy nagasa wasn't there but
his friend
[Music]
was I got a chance to briefly try it
out I had an aversion to getting injured
as I still had a lot more filming to do
so that's my excuse for why I didn't
attempt anything remotely daring
[Music]
after visiting the facility we of course
wondered how this all came about and we
were eventually able to meet up with
Tomy nagasa to find out
I think the opportunity he's been given
is why as an entrepreneur myself kofu
seems like it's full of opportunities
the cost to try a new business idea is
relatively low and the town is quite
supportive of efforts so not only does
he run the BMX facility and BMX related
events in other locations he operates a
screen printing business as well the
downside is that since he's not near
large population centers the amount of
customers he can attract will be much
lower but for someone like Mr Coffee who
also operates out of a different school
he not only sells locally but online as
well it's an opportunity to have a base
that has a low cost but a market that is
Nationwide another thing I thought would
be good to explain is that the building
out of the BMX facilities is partially
funded through a crowdfunding campaign
operated by the city how the furat no
Hometown tax program works is that tax
residents of other areas of Japan can
donate money to support rural areas
whatever they donate up to a certain
amount can be deducted from taxes they
owe so in practice this diverts taxes
from major cities out to rural areas in
return for Their donation donators
sometimes receive gifts like local
produce or Goods although in the case of
this BMX facility there are no giftss
changed something new that has happened
in kofu since we last visited in May of
2023 was the Redevelopment of the area
around kofu interchange Lawson and the
grocery store delivery service and Chan
relocated to the area and then a coin
laundry and beastro noou also took up
shop with the roadside station across
the street that includes a gift shop
restaurant and Farmers Market this area
is the best place to get groceries and
food in town behind the commercial area
they have some some of their public
housing units including some that were
built a few decades ago and some that
were built last year excitingly they're
planning to build a new daycare center
in the area in
2027 it's being partially funded by that
same Hometown tax setup for which
they've already raised 444 of their goal
as of this writing
[Music]
the idea is that it'll be a study abroad
Nursery School which was described like
this it will be a so-called temporary
Nursery School where children attend for
a short period of time such as a few
days to a few months usually temporary
Nursery schools are used for things like
giving birth in a HomeTown but the idea
is to have a Nursery School where
children from families who live in two
locations or who want to relocate can
also be accepted it was pointed out that
this is just a concept at this stage but
it seems like they're off to a promising
start
wow you've made it this far thank you so
much I honestly had a hard time figuring
out how much detail to put into the
video but what I thought I'd do is
gather as much information as possible
for those of you who are serious about
visiting or coming to kofu to live
temporarily or even a little bit more
permanently and what impressed me both
times when visiting the town was that
they seem so open to new ideas and
change and that's kind of seems
counterintuitive when you think about
Japan's Countryside so I hope this came
across in the video and with all the
detail thank you so much for watching
catch you next time peace
join the Discord do the survey links in
the
description for